{
    "id": "dcb8061d5ee0403e8db391be345bde4a",
    "title": "Indirect Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He told me that he …………………………… such a lazy boy as I was.",
            "description": "A past tense in the direct speech will become past perfect in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "never saw",
                "has never seen",
                "had never seen"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "8ce14457a0a14773bf9548568ebabdde"
        },
        {
            "question": "The boy told the girl that he ………………………………. her behavior.",
            "description": "A simple present in the direct speech will become simple past in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "doesn't like",
                "didn't like",
                "hasn't liked"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "aef806dd0b9e459da5c69d729a68eab7"
        },
        {
            "question": "The father told his son that he …………………………… him how to do it.",
            "description": "Will in the direct speech becomes would in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "will show",
                "would show",
                "showed"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0415ea03022b42428aabc2182b96018e"
        },
        {
            "question": "My uncle told me that he …………………………….. me to cinema.",
            "description": "Will in the direct speech becomes would in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "will take",
                "would take"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "37932126f9024291945d8b6580324b70"
        },
        {
            "question": "He told me he …………………………….. to France.",
            "description": "A present continuous in the direct speech becomes past continuous in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "is moving",
                "was moving",
                "had been moving"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b8e9b119f45443c286b43aa0cec8d9e5"
        },
        {
            "question": "He told me that he …………………………………. the parcel the previous day.",
            "description": "A simple past tense in the direct speech will become past perfect in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "sent",
                "had sent",
                "has sent"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e357cc0b80ae416c91d93ea01b4da903"
        },
        {
            "question": "Mary told George that she …………………………… the book on his table the previous day.",
            "description": "A past tense in the direct speech will become past perfect in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "had seen",
                "has seen"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "535c8616a2d14d89a6992d07ed54f2eb"
        },
        {
            "question": "The manager told me that if I …………………………….. late again he would punish me.",
            "description": "A simple present in the direct speech becomes simple past in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "came",
                "had come",
                "have come"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3f376c2efd7d468ab9e9b436b7d9be91"
        },
        {
            "question": "The father told his daughter that he ……………………………… not at all satisfied with her performance at school.",
            "description": "A simple present in the direct speech becomes simple past in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c6afd95fec4d46d08574f587abd8f0a4"
        },
        {
            "question": "He told me that he ……………………………… three snakes in the garden.",
            "description": "A simple past in the direct speech will become past perfect in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "had seen",
                "has seen"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "76374782c6934efdaa7fbdcc486bd031"
        },
        {
            "question": "I reminded him that his wife ………………………………… for him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will be waiting",
                "can be waiting",
                "would be waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "0fd32ae69a6244a28fb6482380e23410"
        },
        {
            "question": "The man asked his servant where he …………………………… the previous day.",
            "description": "A simple past in the direct speech will become past perfect in the indirect speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "26b08a321faa4519b078def77c5aec5f"
        }
    ]
}